So far, we've been looking at simple individual alpha factors.
到目前为止 我们见到的都是简单的单个 alpha 因子
But there are times when we can create factors that are conditioned on another factor.
但有时候我们会基于其他因子创建因子
We can create a conditional factor by multiplying two factors together.
我们可以通过将两个因子相乘 创建条件因子
For example, if factor A gives an alpha value for a single stock,
例如 如果因子 A 为某个股票提供了一个 alpha 值
and factor B gives a different alpha value for that same stock,
因子 B 为同一股票提供了另一个 alpha 值
then we can create a conditioned,
我们可以将这两个单独的 alpha 值相乘
alpha value for that stock by multiplying those two separate alpha values together.
针对该股票创建一个条件 alpha 值
Early on in my career,
在我工作的早期
it was the case that some fairly simple,
有一些很简单的因子
at least as thought of in hindsight today,
至少如今看来很简单
factors could be profitable in live trading.
能够在实时交易中获利
Markets though have become much more competitive as time has marched on and as data,
但是随着时间的推移 涌现出了越来越多的工具和技术
tools, and knowledge have become more available.
市场变得越来越有竞争性
Today, it's likely that you need to find
如今 很有可能需要寻找条件
conditionals to make really good alpha factors as such,
才能创建非常出色的 alpha 因子
this section is critical.
所以这部分知识很重要
So, how do we interpret what this multiplication is doing?
这种乘法的意义是什么？
We'll first look at a common practice in academic papers,
我们先看看学术论文中常见的做法
which we'll refer to as quantiles of quantiles.
称为分位数嵌套分位数
If a research paper is looking at the effects of one factor condition on another,
如果论文研究的是一个因子对另一个因子的影响
they would divide the data into quantiles for one factor.
他们会将一个因子的数据划分成分位数
Let's say we're using 10 decile groups,
假设使用十分位
then within each decile group they would split
然后在每个十分位内
the stocks into another 10 decile groups based on the second factor.
再根据第二个因子划分成十分位
So, now we have 100 quantile groups conditioned on two factors.
现在根据这两个因子划分成了 100 分位
Because we have 10 deciles based on one factor and
因为有 10 个分位数基于一个因子
each decile group has 10 deciles based on the second factor.
每个分位再基于第二个因子划分成十分位
Now, let's see what happens if we create a condition factor based on two factors.
下面看看如何基于这两个因子创建一个条件因子
Let's say we have a stock universe of 100 stocks and we'll convert
假设股票池中有 100 支股票
signal A and signal B into scores from one to 10 for each signal,
我们将信号 A 和信号 B 分别转换成从 1-10 的分数
then we'll calculate the conditional factor as signal A times signal B.
然后计算信号 A 乘以信号 B 的条件因子
Let's pause a moment to think what multiplication means visually.
回忆下乘法的含义
If you remember learning your multiplication tables as a kid,
小时候学习乘法表的时候
you might remember seeing a rectangular grid with a column of
记得有一个长方形表格
numbers 1-10 along the left edge and the numbers 1-10 above the top.
左侧是 1-10 列 顶部是数字 1-10
Multiplying the two numbers for each row and column
将每行和每列的两个数字相乘后
allows us to fill all the boxes inside the multiplication table.
填入乘法表的所有方框中
This is exactly what we're doing with our two factors.
现在两个因子相乘就是这么做
As you can see, the product of A times B,
可以看出 A 与 B 的乘积
ranges from a value of one to a value of a hundred.
值范围从 1 到 100
Notice that, not all the values in between one and 100 are represented,
注意 并没有表示 1-100 之间的所有值
as there are some numbers that occur twice.
因为有些数字出现了两次
However, overall, you can see that there is a range of values between one and a hundred.
但是可以看出值范围从 1 到 100
Does this look familiar to you?
看起来熟悉吗？
When we discuss the process of calculating deciles nested inside deciles,
刚刚讨论十分位嵌套十分位运算时
we also ended up with 100 groups.
也有 100 组
Even though multiplication of the two factors does not give
虽然两个因子相乘
the exact same groupings as we would get from nested quantiles,
并不能完全得出嵌套分位数的分组结果
they have the same goal of creating
但是它们都能根据
a composite factor that is conditioned on the value of both the individual factors.
单个因子的值创建复合因子
We will seek some conditional factors in detail when we
当我们分析研究论文并得出因子理念时
analyze some research papers to generate factor ideas.
我们将寻找一些条件因子
When you read ideas or hypotheses like,
当你遇到一些理念或假说时
stocks that go up on high volume are likely to revert,
例如股价飙升的股票有可能会逆转
or momentum is more pronounced on stocks with low volume,
或者成交量低的股票更有可能保持某一动量
you need to use conditionals.
需要考虑条件因子
Also, whenever you see the word or concept of end,
此外 每当你见到“AND”一词
it is likely that you need to use a conditional.
很有可能需要考虑条件因子